<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.5.1" created="2013-07-04 20:31" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Yannick Lohse</title>
	<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr</link>
	<description>creative coding</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 20:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://yannick-lohse.fr</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://yannick-lohse.fr</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>admin</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>contact@yannick-lohse.fr</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Yannick Lohse]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Yannick]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Lohse]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>About me</title>
		<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr/about-me/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yannick-lohse.fr/?page_id=4</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[If you want to get to know who I am and what I do, you're in the right spot. And if you don't have time for the finer details, <a title="Yannick Lohse - Résumé" href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/cv.pdf">here's my resume</a><em>.</em>
<div class="clearfix">

[caption id="attachment_279" align="alignleft" width="300"]<a href="/about-me/work/"><img class="wp-image-279 " title="Working days" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/dessinjour-300x300.png" alt="Drawing of me, working - during the daytime" width="300" height="300" /></a> <a href="/about-me/work/">Read about my experiences working in the web industry</a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_285" align="alignleft" width="300"]<a href="/about-me/sidework/"><img class="wp-image-285 " title="That's me again, working at night" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/dessinnuit-300x300.png" alt="That's me again, working at night" width="300" height="300" /></a> <a href="/about-me/sidework/">And about the things I've been working on in my free time</a>[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_295" align="alignleft" width="300"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/enveloppe.png"><img class=" wp-image-295 " title="Contact ùe" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/enveloppe-300x300.png" alt="An enveloppe - that's not how you will contact me." width="300" height="300" /></a> And over here there's a contact form, just in case.[/caption]

</div>
<h2>Studies</h2>
I'm French and studied in France. For my High School degree (baccaluréat) I specilized in literature and foreign languages. More specifically, I presented both the French and German high school diplomas (baccalauréat and abitur) and got both. I also earned some fancy English degrees on my way.

I then started my studies. I did a 2 year long DUT called Service et Réseaux de Communications. The name doesn't mean much, but we studied a lot. We focused heavily on computer science, graphic design and communication skills. But we also had project management, law, art, sound&amp;video lessons, etc. A lot of fields related to the interwebz.

Two awesome years. I did learn a lot of things, but most topics were covered quite loosely. The idea was to use the basics taught in class to further expand your skills by working on your own. that worked fairly well for me, and I spent a year and a half coding in Flash, PHP, and creating 3D models in 3DSMax.

I did a final year of studies - something called a "license pro", basically one more year after a DUT to get you a bachelor degree. They are tailored to suit companies needs and make you an effective employee right out of the gates.

<h2>Other things</h2>
[caption id="attachment_416" align="alignright" width="210"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/avatar-petit.png"><img class=" wp-image-416" title="avatar-petit" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/avatar-petit-300x300.png" alt="moi 2012" width="210" height="210" /></a> A picture of me, taken during the summer 2012.[/caption]

I love music. Everyone does. I also play music. i've been playing the guitar for.. uh... 9 years I think. I also sing, but I don't do any concerts. I sometimes play at parties for fun, but it's just a hobby.
A big hobby though. I own 3 guitars, my very last and favorite one is a wonderful <a href="http://www.coleclarkguitars.com/product_fl1.asp">Cole Clark Fat Lady 1</a>. i also own a telecaster and a 12 string guitar.

I'm also doing a lot of sports. I fell in love with Brazilian Jiu Jitsu a year ago and I'm training about 3 times a week since then. It's quite different from other sports; sure there's a lot of technical skills  to master, but it's mainly about strategy - in real time of course. Just like a video game, except it's for real, which makes it a whole lot more fun.

Speaking of video games, I do love to play video games too - I just lack the time to play as much as I would like. i never skip an episode of Assassin's Creed, and I've spent many an hour on the NBA 2K series. I power through other games from time to time (Call of Duty &amp; friends), but I try not to spend too much time playing. It does help charging up my batteries, but I know it's much less productive than say writing my own games.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>4</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-19 22:37:42</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-19 21:37:42</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>about-me</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_rich_snippet_type</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Yannick Lohse | About me]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Let me tell you more about who I man, what I enjoy and what I've done over the last couple of years]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-noindex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-nofollow</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-adv</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-include</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-prio</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_canonical</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_redirect</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Work</title>
		<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr/about-me/work/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 21:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yannick-lohse.fr/?page_id=6</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[I have been working full time for two and a half straight years now ; but I've had professional experiences before. Here's what I've been doing strictly professionally speaking.

<h2>Too Long ; Didn't Read</h2>
I tried to make it short, but it's a long story anyway. Here's the quick version :
<ul>
	<li>I did a couple of hard and uninteresting summer jobs</li>
	<li>Over the course of 5 months in 2 years, I was a trainee in a Swiss company, working on their secondary products as a developer</li>
	<li>Over a year, I had an alternation contract at a local web company, where I worked as lead developer.</li>
	<li>Since 2and a half years now, I work at <a title="Groupe ESC Troyes" href="http://get-formation.fr/">Groupe ESC Troyes</a> - I created the new "<a title="This is my baby." href="http://get-formation.fr/">flagship website</a>", and manage/create other ones</li>
</ul>

<h2>Summer jobs</h2>
I set out to get my first summer job when I became 16 - when it becomes legal to work in France. I worked at a do-it-all boy in my city (gardening, cleaning the grounds, etc), and then at a metal factory in Switzerland, again mainly cleaning metal pieces, loading trails of metal pieces, straightening metal pieces... well, you get the idea. Not really great, and definitely not related to Computer Science - but you really appreciate to work in an office after you've been through working at a factory.

Speaking of offices...
<h2>Intern ships</h2>
[caption id="attachment_410" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/screen1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-410 " title="GIS map" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/screen1-300x225.jpg" alt="GIS Map" width="300" height="225" /></a> A screenshot of the tool I created in my 2nd internship at CAD Rechenzentrum[/caption]

At nearly 18, I was in my first year of studies, and we had to do a 2 week intern ship in any company. A week before the start of the intern ship, I still hadn't found a company I could do my intern ship at - or rather I hadn't been looking around a lot. One of my best friends dad happened to own a <a title="CADRZ" href="http://www.cadrz.ch/content.cfm?nav=2&amp;content=5">software company in Switzerland</a>, and he was nice enough to hire me.

Life as a trainee there was excellent - they let me do real work, on internal products. The two weeks went great, and I asked if I could stay to work over the summer. The company being happy with my work so far, this wasn't a problem at all and I worked there for 2 more month, mainly helping debugging a software used to sync user accounts between different systems.

Boy did I learn a lot about programming.

When in my second year I had to do another, longer intern ship, I very naturally went back to the <a title="CAD Rechenzentrum" href="http://www.cadrz.ch/content.cfm?nav=2&amp;content=5">CAD Rechenzentrum</a> - and this time I worked on a client product. The company mainly produces a software for the state of Switzerland to manage their (oh so many) bridges and tunnels. I worked on a <a title="KUBA Web" href="http://www.cadrz.ch/content.cfm?nav=34&amp;content=56">map displayed in a webpage</a> used to indicate the location of the different constructions, with map images that the company owned. You could pan the map, zoom in/out, and click the locations to get details on them - all of it done in javascript.

<h2>First steps in the web industry</h2>


<img class="wp-image-374 alignright" title="Logo_Kairos_media_Pro" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/kairosmediapro-300x36.jpg" alt="Kairos Media Pro Logo" width="300" height="36" />
During my last year at the university in 2009, I had the opportunity to study in alternation, ie. studying a week at the university, then working a week for a company. I was hired by a business called Kairos Media and worked there for a year.

[caption id="attachment_376" align="alignleft" width="300"]<a href="http://www.mesinvendus.fr"><img class="wp-image-376 " title="mesinvendus" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/mesinvendus-300x184.jpg" alt="Screenshot of mesinvendus.fr" width="300" height="184" /></a> MesInvendus.fr, the flagship of Kairos Media.[/caption]

Kairos Media's main activity was maintaining 2 websites providing newspaper resellers with useful tools. As their lead developer, I developed several new features, updated existing ones and fixed a lot of stuff around the website. Requirements would often change during the coding phases, there was absolutely no process or work flow. The code of the site was very old and flawed all over the place - writing clean code in such a messy environment wasn't easy.

But I learned new skills nonetheless there. I was already a good developer when I arrived, but nothing more - I expected to be told what to do, and then I would proceed coding it. But things didn't work that way in a small business; I was often times asked to give my opinion on new products or services, to deliver time estimates or to create ads myself... Being the technical referrer made me grow to a whole new level, and by the end of the year I would often be the one suggesting changes to improve the business.

It didn't prove enough though; over the course of the year, the CEO had to let go half of the crew. And at the end of the year, they were close to shutting down the whole business - from a 10 person crew when I joined, we would shrink down to a 3 person team. My alternation contract was for a year, but I was offered a long term contract... that I chose to decline. We were often paid late, I would have to work from my home, and I felt the company was marching towards it's end.

<h2>A "real" job</h2>
<img class="wp-image-364 alignleft" title="Logo GET" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/getlogo.png" alt="Thelogo of Groupe ESC Troyes" width="210" height="160" />
With two weeks left to work at Kairos Media and no intention to stay any longer, I had to start looking for a job. Before I really had a chance to work out a plan, another opportunity presented itself. At the university, I ran into a man talking with one of my friends, who had done his year in alternation in the local business school. He wasn't going to keep the job, so I knew the position was open.

I asked my future boss if the position was indeed open. It was, and I quickly got my first real job, without even sending a resume - they were in a hurry and looked it up themselves before I even moved a finger. it was a long term contract too. All good.

[caption id="attachment_368" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://get-formation.fr"><img class="wp-image-368 " title="Screenshot GET" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/screenget-300x181.png" alt="A screenshot of the website I did for Groupe ESC Troyes" width="300" height="181" /></a> Groupe ESC Troyes's main website, that I built from scratch.[/caption]

The company is called <a title="Groupe ESC Troyes" href="http://get-formation.fr/">Groupe ESC Troyes</a> and I still work there today. It's been two and a half years now and everything went just fine. It's more than just a business school - we provide education in management, tourism, design... We have departments dealing with education for unemployed people, for teenagers coming out of jail.... <a href="http://get-formation.fr/groupe-esc-troyes">Well they have a website that tells it all</a>.

In those two years, I developed a bunch of new websites to help us promote our different activities and events we organize. I worked on internal as well as external applications, always web based. But most importantly, after one year there, we started a complete redesign of the aging website. Not only graphical redesign, the whole code base would change as well to meet new requirements.

It took us roughly 6 month of work - the website was huge, around 300 different pages and 20 different layouts. The content management had to work on a separate website and the publication system needed several level of validation. The communication agency that had created our new logo designed a couple of page layouts, and I did the remaining ones.  The project was warmly greeted - user testing gave excellent results and statistics rose.

Again, I think I grew a lot in this job - so much that I changed the way I called myself. I was a developer coming in, a bearded programmer to whom design and integration was a mere necessity. I now define myself as a front-end developer - while I still enjoy long hours of pure coding, my design skills improved a lot. And with them, understanding of the complexity that resides in user interface design, interaction design and usability. I am know very aware of the problems and love to tackle them. In the same time, HTMl &amp; CSS evolved; instead of stacking divs and writing tons of css to get a decent browser support, we can now focus on semantics and page speed optimization, changes that made front-end development a very interesting challenge.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>6</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-19 22:38:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-19 21:38:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>work</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>4</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>1</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_rich_snippet_type</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Yannick Lohse | My working experiences as a web developper]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Find out about the different positions I held in my life as a programmer / web developer / front-end developer / designer.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-noindex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-nofollow</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-adv</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-include</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-prio</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_canonical</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_redirect</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title> Sidework</title>
		<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr/about-me/sidework/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 21:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yannick-lohse.fr/?page_id=8</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[As far as I know, I always loved to spend time and efforts in projects that were not directly related nor asked by my school, and later by my employers. <a title="Blog" href="/">My blog itself</a> is made of those, but there are projects that I have worked on for longer timespans- and I'd like to talk about them. They make up fora huge part of my life in the past years, so it's fairly long - but I provide a tl;dr version.
<h2>Too Long ; Didn't read</h2>
[caption id="attachment_406" align="alignright" width="260"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Photo_012906_008.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-406" title="Me old" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/Photo_012906_008-300x225.jpg" alt="An old picture of me" width="260" height="195" /></a> A picture of me, back in 2009[/caption]
<ul>
	<li>At 16, I became moderator on the <a href="http://forum.travian.fr/">official travian forum</a></li>
	<li>I remained in the team for several years, and eventually became board admin at only 17</li>
	<li>At the end, internal conflicts made most of the crew resign- including me</li>
	<li>With a couple of friends I met on travian, we set out to create our own browser game</li>
	<li>This kept us busy for the next 3-4 years, during which I learned a lot</li>
	<li>After starting my first job, I found myself unable to keep working on the game and left</li>
	<li>I did nothing but work for 2 years (ie. no side projects)</li>
	<li>After attending Web Event Lyon, I decided to start side projects again</li>
	<li>Since then I've released a site called Look At Stream and I am working on other things.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Travian</h2>
As I said, I always loved to invest my spare time and side projects. But back in 2005, I was going through high school and lacked any of the skills required to build something from the ground up. So instead, I spent a lot of time playing online games. I was playing a brand new game called <a title="Travian" href="http://www.travian.fr/">travian</a>. That's right, I played browser based games instead of fancy MMORPGs.

[caption id="attachment_393" align="alignleft" width="300"]<img class=" wp-image-393 " title="travian screen" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/def-famille-300x228.jpg" alt="Screenshot oftravian" width="300" height="228" /> Travian used to look like this.[/caption]

A part from the game itself, I also spent countless hours on the <a href="http://forum.travian.fr/">community boards</a> and on the IRC channel. The community was brand new, there was almost no team to take are of the game. So I started answering many questions from newcomers on the boards, and helping out were I could. The satisfaction of helping people really was the sole motivation, and it had better be - there were no rewards ahead.

After a year or so, <a title="Travian Games" href="http://www.traviangames.com/en.html">the company behind the game</a> hired an admin to take care of the french community, and he in turn started recruiting a team to help him. I became forum moderator, and loved every bit of it; I started out answering questions (just like I used to do), but also had to keep my part of the forum clean, locking and moving topics, and making sure every thing was in check. At some point I started spending more time being a moderator (on the irc chan as well) than playing the actual game.

I was about to turn 17 and was offered a higher position - I became a super-moderator. I was in charge of the whole forum - at that time around 2000 active users and divided into over 15 parts. But I would also participate in recruiting new moderators, training and teaching them how to keep their part of the forum alive, but under control ; they had to be firm, but not tyrannic.

I wasn't aware of it, but I was going through my first experience as a manager. I think I did ok : with the 2 people occupying similar positions to mine, we brought the forum team from a 5-6 men crew to a full 15 person staff, all of them trained and - I guess - happy to do their volunteer job. Because yes, all of this was of course volunteering, even though I spent roughly 4 hours a day in this, and much more on week ends.

Managing a team proved itself somewhat more stressful than just moderating forums, but again, I took great pleasure in doing it. The job itself was nice, but the team we had built was great. They were a bunch of very fun and interesting people, and when we weren't busy working, we we're happily chatting together on irc.

[caption id="attachment_401" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/cucuchocoglorflounswil.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-401 " title="irl travian" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/cucuchocoglorflounswil-300x225.jpg" alt="A photo of me and some crewmembers" width="300" height="225" /></a> During one of our "In Real Life" meetups with the travian team. I'm the long haired guy in the middle.[/caption]

This was around 2007, and the forum admin decided to quit. He was one of the 2 companions we had built the team with, and I was chosen to replace him. At only 17, I became admin of a board that had over 3000 active users, and head of a 20 persons crew I had been recruiting myself. I was proud and happy, and things kicked out well.

However, things went somewhat down the drain over the course of the next monthes. Several changes at the head of the team made most of us leave - including me.
Management itself left a bitter taste; I learned that taking responsibilities without sound reason is quite a bad idea, and was better at doing things than telling people how to do them.

<h2>Eclypsis</h2>
[caption id="attachment_394" align="alignright" width="203"]<img class=" wp-image-394 " title="top5" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/top5.jpg" alt="Screeenshot of the top 10" width="203" height="233" /> The top 10 looters on the server - the 5 best are from our clan. When I say we ruled, I mean it.[/caption]

During all this time, I rarely stopped playing the game itself, and by the start of 2007 I was amongst the best players in France. I met a guy for the second time ingame - we had briefly been friends a year ago, before loosing sight of each other. At the start of a new travian server, <a title="Matthieu's portfolio" href="http://urls.fr/pms">Matthieu </a>(that's his name) gathered a couple of friends to create a clan, and I was among them. We quickly took over the whole server. We were the best clan, composed of about 30 players, all of them ranking in the top 50, 10 of them in the top 20. We ruled over our virtual lands like tyrants, which also happens to be our clan name. We lied, we betrayed, we stole - lots of fun.

A couple of months later, I would quit my position as forum admin, and this was a clear signal that travian was going downwards. 6 more month of disastrous management and players would start looking elsewhere - or at least that's what we figured. Among the people in the clan, there was another friend of Matthieu's, who knew how to code. He told both of us he had ideas for a travian like game, but without its flaws; all he needed was our programming skills.

As developers, we knew the task was huge; but we didn't realize how huge exactly. We agreed.

[caption id="attachment_397" align="alignleft" width="179"]<img class="wp-image-397  " title="eclypsis logo" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/blog-header.png" alt="eclypsis logo" width="179" height="154" /> One of the logos for our game[/caption]

Pierre and I would take care of the PHP and javascript code. I hired another friend of mine to handle the html & css, and we went out searching for a designer while starting to work on the game. We learned a lot - I got better and better at programming.I already knew everything there was to know about the programing language itself; but I also understood that pure technical knowledge didn't make you a food programmer. I needed understanding of broader concepts, of software architecture and design. The team eventually met "in real life", spent 4 days in the front-end developers parent house coding night and day. A couple of designers came and went. We spent countless hours working on the project.

[caption id="attachment_395" align="alignright" width="258"]<a href="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/superheropingpong.jpg"><img class="wp-image-395 " title="pingpong irl" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/superheropingpong-300x225.jpg" alt="Pierre and me playing ping pong" width="258" height="193" /></a> Pierre and me playing pingpong during one of the eclypsis meetups. And yes, we just play <strong>that</strong> fast.[/caption]

2009 arrived and a new designer started to work with us. This was also the rise of HTML5, and front end development became appealing to me. The other frond end developer, Clowrid, left the project, so I took over the front end part. The PHP code base was now advanced enough so that Pierre could handle the remaining parts alone. I set out to create and code the new game UI with our designer.

Over the years, there had been several difficult phases, where the project had been stuck. At times I had been coding alone for weeks; at other times Pierre did the same. It was hard to keep the motivation up over such a long time span, especially without being able to show of the result or get feedback.

[caption id="attachment_399" align="alignleft" width="300"]<img class=" wp-image-399 " title="eclypsis old" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/1-300x239.png" alt="Screenshot of eclypsis" width="300" height="239" /> A former game interface for Eclypsis[/caption]

One year later, I was done with my studies and immediately started my first real job. Eclypsis - the name of the game - needed more or less 6 more month of work before the beta. I did try to keep working on it; but after 3 month at my new job I had a burn out and needed to spend my freetimes on other things then coding.... so i left the project.

Eclypsis went live a couple of months later, re-branded  <a href="http://www.nemeria.com/">Nemeria</a>. I asked if I could help again, either by investing money in the company or through my experience as a board admin, but the proposal was rejected. I was disappointed, but I now had a very interesting job that had to focus on. I had become a very good developer, both on the front and back end. I learned the value of software design, code DRYness and other similar concepts. Other side projects helped, but Eclypsis most of all thought me what I now know about programming.

<h2>Look at stream and the future</h2>

For the 2 next years, I almost didn't write a line of code outside my work. My job had been exiting, and again, I had become much better. My previously in-existent design skills had grown by necessity, and I was now good enough to handle any web project almost on my own.

[caption id="attachment_403" align="alignright" width="188"]<a href="http://lookatstream.com"><img class=" wp-image-403 " title="LAS logo" src="http://yannick-lohse.fr/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/logo_hr-300x211.png" alt="The look at stream logo" width="188" height="131" /></a> The Look At Stream logo, courtesy of my friend <a title="Loic's website" href="http://herrloc.fr/">Loic Herr</a>[/caption]

I want to my first ever conference, <a href="http://event.lafermeduweb.net/">the Web Event Lyon</a>. For the very first time in my life, I met many other developers, designers, and people working in the same field than I did. The talks they gave were awesome, and they the motivation I had lost returned. About a week later, I was skyping with Clowrid, the other front end developer from Eclypsis who had remained a close friend over the years. He had a good knowledge of the professional gaming environment and was building a new site called <a title="Live streams from the biggest games out there" href="http://lookatstream.com/">look at stream</a>. He asked if I wanted to help out - I hesitated a split second and said yes.

I spent 3 straight days designing the site and rewriting most of the code that was already there - and we launched. The site simply allows the users to watch live streams from games like League of Legends or Starcraft 2, originally displayed on <a href="http://www.own3d.tv/">own3d.tv</a> or <a href="http://www.twitch.tv/">twitch</a>. Clowrid used his contact network to start promoting the site, and it has been doing fairly well since then : the user base is constantly growing and we reach pretty high traffic peaks during big tournaments. We recently created an organization around the website that could hold the rights and cash in the incomes.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-19 22:38:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-19 21:38:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>sidework</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>4</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>2</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_rich_snippet_type</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Yannick Lohse | Projects I participate in during my free time]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_description</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[I've always spent a lot fo my free time working on projects with or without goals - they have lead me to great experiences, which I relate here.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_focuskw</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_title</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_metadesc</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-noindex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-nofollow</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_meta-robots-adv</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-include</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_sitemap-prio</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_canonical</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_redirect</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Contact</title>
		<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr/about-me/contact/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 14:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yannick-lohse.fr/?page_id=42</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Please feel free to contact me for anything - questions, feedback, what ever. I'll be gladto get backto you as soon as I can. You can also send me an email right away : contact-at-yannick-lohse.fr
<div id="contactform">[customcontact form=1]</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>42</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-26 15:55:01</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-26 14:55:01</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>contact</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>4</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[contact.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_rich_snippet_type</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Contact confirmed</title>
		<link>http://yannick-lohse.fr/about-me/contact/contact-confirmed/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 17:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yannick-lohse.fr/?page_id=330</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Thanks, your message has successfully been sent to me. I'll get back to you if necessary.

You may now get back to <a title="Back to the blog" href="/">the blog</a> or the part <a href="/about-me/">about me</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>330</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-03 18:08:09</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-03 17:08:09</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>contact-confirmed</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>42</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[contact.php]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_su_rich_snippet_type</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[none]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_yoast_wpseo_linkdex</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
